<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OSRD – Strategic choices</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/program/strategic-choices/</link><description>Recent content in Strategic choices on OSRD</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/program/strategic-choices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Who-We-Are: Open-Source</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/program/strategic-choices/opensource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/program/strategic-choices/opensource/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;font color=#aa026d>« The OSRD application is open source. The simulations are transparent, explicit and universal. Any actor willing to improve the competitiveness of the railway system can contribute to it »&lt;/font>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Loïc Hamelin, OSRD Project Manager at DGEX Solutions (Direction Générale Exploitation de SNCF Réseau)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="font-coloraa026dosrd--when-railway-simulation-becomes-open-sourcefont">&lt;font color=#aa026d>OSRD : when railway simulation becomes open source&lt;/font>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The choice of open source is particularly strategic in the public sector. In addition to significantly lowering development costs, it offers every citizen &lt;strong>the transparency needed&lt;/strong> to understand and evaluate public investment choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We believe that Open Source addresses political, economic, technical and even energy issues:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Political&lt;/strong>, through transparency and uniformity, because it is necessary to regain the confidence of our sponsors and because standards are struggling to be established in the sector  &lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Economic&lt;/strong>, because a better use of the network will reduce the costs of operating and owning the network, and because the objective is to make the rail mode even more attractive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Technical&lt;/strong>, because sharing allows evolution&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Energy&lt;/strong>, finally, because we can accelerate the energy transition by enhancing the value of rail transport. But we must do so while maintaining or improving industrial performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Finally, open source allows to federate a community of people who worked until then in their corner. Everything is based on (Bill) Joy&amp;rsquo;s famous law : &lt;em>&lt;font color=#aa026d>« No matter who you are, most of the smartest people work for someone else »&lt;/font>&lt;/em> !&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="font-coloraa026ddefinition-font">&lt;font color=#aa026d>Definition :&lt;/font>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Open source consists in leaving the source code of a developed software freely available, so that anyone can &lt;strong>read it, use it and propose modifications or developments&lt;/strong>. The design and development of open source software is then placed in the hands of &lt;strong>communities&lt;/strong> of users and/or developers.
Everyone has the ability to adapt the software to their own requirements and needs, while sharing their innovations with a large community. Development goals are therefore shared: bugs, the status of their resolution and the efforts made to solve them are public, as is the progress of new features.
In absolute terms, &lt;strong>anyone who wants to can contribute to the project, but this does not mean that any proposed change will be integrated :&lt;/strong> just like peer reviews in the scientific community, open source communities have their own standards, requirements, and code reviews. The goal is clear: to ensure that the project remains of good quality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who-We-Are: Open-Data</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/program/strategic-choices/opendata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/program/strategic-choices/opendata/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>