<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OSRD – Projects/solutions</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/</link><description>Recent content in Projects/solutions on OSRD</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Who-We-Are: Strategic timetable</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/strategic-timetable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/strategic-timetable/</guid><description>
&lt;font color=#aa026d>
&lt;h3 id="presentation">Presentation&lt;/h3>
&lt;/font>
&lt;p>A first phase of the transportation plan design process starts very early: Y-10 of the day the train is to run and aims to &lt;strong>propose several traffic scenarios&lt;/strong> on existing or prospective rail infrastructure. In this phase, SNCF Réseau, the French railway infrastructure manager and responsible for the allocation and sale of train paths, collects requests from &lt;strong>OA&lt;/strong> (Organizing Authorities) and &lt;strong>RC&lt;/strong> (Railway Companies) in terms of mobility. The requests will be transmitted in the form of &lt;strong>service plans&lt;/strong>. A service plan is a way of representing the requested trains, their route and the stops to be served.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>OSRD Strategic Schedules&lt;/strong> product has been designed to build an operating plan from the service diagrams, based on &lt;strong>rail infrastructure modeling, running calculation and simulation&lt;/strong>. Building an operating plan means scheduling the trains presented on the service diagrams in a way that best meets the mobility needs. The OSRD tool provides a database with a &lt;strong>micro-model of the French railway infrastructure&lt;/strong> as well as the &lt;strong>rolling stock already in use in France&lt;/strong>. Moreover, an interface to modify the existing infrastructure or to design a new part of the infrastructure is proposed. The output products of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>OSRD Strategic Schedules&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; process are timetables where the train schedules are displayed. A graphical representation of the timetables is thus proposed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A comprehensive and strategic view of the timetable planning is crucial to improve rail performance. &lt;strong>The ultimate goal is to meet mobility needs by optimizing line capacity utilization, station track occupancy and material turnover&lt;/strong>. To meet this optimization requirement, we are working to implement mathematical modeling and resolution modules coupled with the simulator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who-We-Are: Exploitation studies</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/exploitation-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/exploitation-studies/</guid><description>
&lt;font color=#aa026d>
&lt;h3 id="presentation">Presentation&lt;/h3>
&lt;/font>
&lt;p>Millions of Euros are invested each year in rail projects on the basis of operational studies. The objectives of these studies are &lt;strong>to match transport needs with the rail infrastructure and to assess the capacity of the network to meet these needs&lt;/strong>. Operational studies, which are strategic and crucial for informing public investment decisions concerning the future of the rail network and for the performance of the rail system, require rare and exclusive skills and &lt;strong>currently produce scattered and poorly capitalized data&lt;/strong>. For this reason, SNCF Réseau has chosen in 2019 to equip itself with an in-house tool to carry out these studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>OSRD Operational Studies&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo; project was born in response to the shortcomings of the market: numerous and expensive tools, closed and with non-comparable results. On the contrary, we propose a reference tool accessible to all, whose results are transparent, explicit and universal. The OSRD tool provides a database with a microscopic modeling of the French railway infrastructure (gradients, radii of curvature, limiting speeds). An interface to modify the existing infrastructure or to design a new part of the infrastructure is proposed.
Thanks to this modeling and to its running calculation engine, OSRD can calculate routes, draw paths, simulate trains and their interaction with the signaling system.
OSRD meets the &lt;strong>stakes of sustainable mobility&lt;/strong> by optimizing energy consumption. The expected regularity margin on the running of a train is distributed according to an &lt;strong>algorithm that minimizes the energy consumed by the train during the journey&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting element of verification of an exploitation scenario is &lt;strong>the evaluation of the robustness&lt;/strong> of what is projected. For this function, a &lt;strong>stochastic simulation module&lt;/strong> is proposed. Hazards can be modeled and injected into the simulator to evaluate the consequences and the ability of the system to return to balance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who-We-Are: Infrastructure management</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/infrastructure-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/infrastructure-management/</guid><description>
&lt;font color=#aa026d>
&lt;h3 id="presentation">Presentation&lt;/h3>
&lt;/font>
&lt;p>Several applications used within the SNCF group and outside need a &lt;strong>mapping representation of the railway network&lt;/strong>. The OSRD base map uses geographic data from &lt;strong>OpenStreetMap (OSM)&lt;/strong>, a &amp;ldquo;Wikipedia of maps&amp;rdquo; that allows collaborative consultation and editing of geographic data. This base map is regularly updated to reflect the evolution of non-rail infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../osrd_management.png" alt="OSRD management">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;OSRD Infrastructure Management**&amp;rdquo; proposes a mapping service accessible to all and shared, based on the same model: everyone will be able to contribute and put in quality the railway data.
We provide on the one hand a &lt;strong>complete editor of the rail network infrastructure and the objects that compose it&lt;/strong>, and on the other hand, &lt;strong>the provision of data layers for their exploitation and representation in the standards of online mapping&lt;/strong>. Finally, we are studying the possibility of **being able to automate the updating of OpenStreetMap&amp;rsquo;s railway data** with the data thus made available.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who-We-Are: Short term digital capacity management</title><link>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/short-term-dcm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dgexsolutions.github.io/osrd-website/en/who-we-are/project/short-term-dcm/</guid><description>
&lt;font color=#aa026d>
&lt;h3 id="definition">Definition&lt;/h3>
&lt;/font>
&lt;p>In order to define the Short Term Digital Capacity Management (STDCM) path, we first need to define what a path is, as well as the actors involved. A &lt;strong>path&lt;/strong> is the reservation of space/time on the network. It is an &lt;strong>RC&lt;/strong> (railway company) that orders the path, and the &lt;strong>IM&lt;/strong> (infrastructure manager) that provides the route. When we talk about &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; train paths, the reservation request is made several years in advance (A-3), and the IM produces a document in which we can find all the requests with their assigned capacity on the network. &lt;strong>Capacity&lt;/strong> is the total amount of track available on the rail network of a IM. It is divided between commercial capacity, intended for RCs, and work capacity, which, as its name indicates, is reserved for the various works planned on the tracks. As a preventive measure and in order to be able to manage certain contingencies (delays, technical or environmental problems), the rate of reserved train paths may not exceed 75% of the total capacity of the network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where the last minute groove comes in. If there are no problems, the IM is left with about 25% of its capacity unused. So if an RC needs a path urgently (between A-1 and up to a few minutes before the rolling stock is due to depart), it can apply for a STDCM.&lt;/p>
&lt;font color=#aa026d>
&lt;h3 id="challenges-and-ambitions">Challenges and ambitions&lt;/h3>
&lt;/font>
&lt;p>The STDCMs are currently managed by the capacity counter between A-1 and D-1, and by the operational counter from D-1 to 5 pm. Several problems arise from this; the request is tedious and the response from the counters is asynchronous (taking several days to respond), the paths are traced by hand (risk of human error) and the billing can get lost in the operations, it is estimated that tens of millions of euros are lost due to unbilled STDCM. Some digital tools already know how to solve these problems, but they do not take into account conflict management on the network, or if they do, they do not know how to manage it at the station.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is in response to these challenges that the idea of offering digital management of last-minute train paths was born. The objective is to allow RCs to book train paths easily, by proposing a calculation of the STDCM within the theoretical forecast capacity, and by providing them with a quick response (about 3 minutes waiting time). Customers could also choose between several calculation modes. This tool is under development and should be available in the next few years.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>